http://www.bristol.anglican.org/legal/

Safeguarding
HomeAbout usContact usStaff directorySenior clergySafeguardingSafeguarding concernSafeguarding informationSafeguarding Resources for PSOs and ParishesSafeguarding Resources for ParishesParish Safeguarding DashboardSafeguarding trainingVictims and survivors of abuseSafeguarding GovernancePast Case Review 2GovernanceBishop's CouncilGeneral SynodDiocesan SynodDeanery SynodsPCCsRegistrarBristol Uganda LinkUganda informationA brief history of the nationClimateA brief history of the ChurchUganda Link newsUganda galleryTravel adviceChurch LifeOur churchesFind a ChurchBristol CathedralDeaneriesResourcing Churches Mission AreasMission Areas' and Resourcing churches' NewsBaptisms, weddings and funeralsBaptismsWeddingsFuneralsResources for prayerDiocesan Cycle of PrayerTry PrayingThy Kingdom ComeResources for parishesHow to... guidesEnvironment and Climate JusticeChildren and young people's ministryEMERGE courseCommunion before ConfirmationLife to the MaxMaking Disciples in Your ParishA foundation of prayerCreating a culture of invitationCreative family-focused expressions of churchOpportunities to explore the Christian faithSmall groups for
whole-life discipleshipDevelopings the gifts of God's peopleJourney of InvitationSafe and Welcome AwardsAccessibilityResources for mission and evangelismMission supportWhat is evangelism?Worship and liturgyCreative ArtsParish Share, stewardship and financeGiving ResourcesParish ShareParish Giving Scheme Guidance for treasurersFundraising and trustsContactlessFees for weddings and funerals LegaciesParish BuyingParish Finance ForumParish AdministrationChurch buildingsDACPublic NoticesParish Officer Forms and guidanceHR advice and guidance for parishesSerious Incident ReportingData Protection: Parishes and 'GDPR'Resources for ministersClergy HandbookClergy Ministerial DevelopmentMDRClergy and families' well-beingSpirituality and Spiritual DirectionHousingRetreats for ministersRetired ClergyResilience workshopsDealing with conflictCounselling for clergySt Luke's Healthcare for the ClergyVocations: Is God calling you?How do I discern my calling?Licensed Lay MinistryOrdained ministryCEMESExploring ChristianityEducationOur schoolsOur Vision and ApproachEducation Team and Board of EducationResources for schoolsRE resourcesRE Agreed Syllabus for BristolRE Agreed Syllabus for South GlosRE Agreed Syllabus for SwindonRE Agreed Syllabus for WiltshireRE to save the planetWIRE AwardSIAMS resourcesSMSC resourcesCollective Worship resourcesTraining, consultancy and support for schoolsLeadership Development and Headship AppointmentInspire Conference resourcesChurch-School linksChurch School Partnership AwardINSPIRE mentorsChurch School link case studiesIdeas and adviceSchool organisation and governanceGovernanceSchool Foundation GovernorsAdmissionsSchool buildings and capitalDiocese of Bristol Academies Company (DoBAC)Home SchoolingResourcesVision and PrioritiesTransforming Church2016-2020 Vision and Priorities101 ideas
Legal
Home > Homepage Widgets & Footers
> Legal
Homepage Widgets & FootersFrom the BishopsView vacancies
Legal information, cookies and disclaimers
The Bristol Diocesan Board of Finance is a limited company registered in England.
Registered number: 156243.
Charity number: 248502
Registered office:
Hillside House, 1500 parkway North, Stoke Gifford, Bristol BS34 8YU
Tel: 0117 906 0100
Cookies and opt-out
Since a change in EU internet law, we’re required to inform you of the following information regarding cookies.
Our website occasionally uses a technology known as cookies to store small amounts of data on our visitors’ computers or devices. You’ll have come across them if you log into any intranet or webmail and find you’re still logged in when you next visit that secure page… that functionality is down to… cookies!
By using this website you agree that we can place cookies on your computer unless you change your browser settings. Our cookies cannot be used to identify you. In fact, we believe there is no reason for any concern over any of the cookies used on our website; however certain users may have privacy concerns or consider some cookies to be intrusive. Below we outline what cookies we use and why, to help you make an informed choice.
You may set your browser to reject cookies or to notify you when a web site tries to place cookies in your browser program. Please consult with your browser documentation for instructions on how to do this.
These are cookies set by ourselves or the software running on our website. These are generally required for correct operation of certain parts of the website and generally only last for the duration of your browser session.
We have listed our first-party cookies below, along with their purpose and expiry period.
First-Party Cookies
Name: Analytics
Expires: At the end of your session (when you close your browser)
Analytics is a tool made by Google, which we use to track visitor statistics. We do not store any information in this (session) cookie, although it is generated automatically when you visit our site, and simply gives us an idea of how many visitors we have to our pages.
Name: Anglican.org
Expires: At the end of your session (when you close your browser)
These are the international owners of the Anglican.org domain, of which all Diocesan websites are subdomains (oxford.anglican.org, bathwells.anglican.org etc etc). We do not store any information in this (session) cookie, although it is generated automatically when you visit our site.
Third-Party Cookies
Some of the functionality of the site uses third-party plugins, for example social media buttons (Facebook, Twitter etc.). These may use cookies created by such a third-party service and although we have chosen to integrate the services with our website, we do not have control over the cookies set by these services.
We use these services as a convenience to our visitors and on the basis that the providing party adheres to their privacy and/or data use policies. (See Further Information below).
Because they are outside our control, the detail of these cookies may change, so we have listed some information and links about the respective third parties to help you find out more. The actual cookies may also vary depending whether you are logged into those social media sites when browsing our website.
Youtube videos:
YouTube is owned by Google.
View the Google Privacy Policy.
Controlling and Blocking Cookies
We do not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information about you. However, if you wish to block cookies from this website (or any other), you can do so by modifying your browser settings. Your browser’s Help function should advise you on how to do this. For more information about cookies, visit http://www.aboutcookies.org.
Copyright advice
Any resources of the Bristol Diocese website are free for reproduction in your Parish newsletter, magazine or website. However, if you produce a newsletter or website which is not directly affiliated with the Diocese (a ‘local digest’ magazine for example, or news from another religion/denomination) and you would like to use these resources, please gain permission from our Communications Officer.
All images on the internet belong to someone, using images (or any other media) you didn’t produce yourself is a breach of copyright. Whether you use the image for non-profit or religious purposes makes no difference; you are still at risk if you do not have permission to use images on your website or in your Parish Magazine. Legal settlement normally means a fine of around £1,500-£3,000 for breach of copyright.
The simplest way to avoid legal difficulties is to search for ‘Creative Commons’ licensed images from a website like Flickr (select the “Only search within Creative Commons-licensed content” option before running your image search). You could also purchase images from a stock imagery website such as iStockPhoto or even take the photos yourself – you automatically own copyright of your own photos.
Public information policy
Our online policy for Clergy/Diocesan Officers’ personal data is that business contact information will be shared, but anything more will require your consent. So our online info may include:
your name
your work email address
your work contact phone number
Our online info will not include (without your consent):
a photo of you
your home contact details.
This applies to all Diocesan websites, searchable Diocesan Databases online. If at any stage you think more information is available online about you than you are happy with, please contact the Diocesan Office to make changes.
Disclaimer
Covering the websites of The Diocese of Bristol
For specific requests not outlined in this Terms & Conditions statement, please contact The Diocese of Bristol.
1. Acceptance Of Terms
This is a Website of The Diocese of Bristol. Use by you of this Website and any other websites operated by The Diocese of Bristol and its group companies to which this Website is linked (the “The Diocese of Bristol sites”), together with all associated servers (“Servers”) and all of the functions on or in or available from this
Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or the Servers (including, without limitation all chat forums, bulletin boards or other forms of communication) is subject to the following terms and conditions (“Terms and Conditions”) and any other terms and conditions contained on, in or available through a Diocese of Bristol Site.
2. Content
The copyright in the material contained on, in, or available through this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server excluding the Content (as defined in paragraph 3) but including all other information, data, text, music, sound, photographs, graphics, video messages or other materials and the selection and arrangement thereof, and all source code, software compilations and other material (“Material”) is owned by or licensed to The Diocese of Bristol or its group companies. All rights are reserved. You do not have any right, interest or title in or to the Material unless otherwise expressly indicated.
The trademarks, service marks, and logos (“Trade Marks”) contained on or in this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server are registered and owned by or licensed to The Diocese of Bristol or its group companies. Save as expressly stated, you do not have any right to use, copy, edit, vary, reproduce, publish, display, distribute, store, transmit, commercially exploit or disseminate the Trade Marks without the prior written consent of The Diocese of Bristol or the relevant group company.
You are permitted to print or download extracts of the Material for your personal use only provided that each copy contains a notice that the Material is owned by or licensed to The Diocese of Bristol or its group companies. None of the Material may be used for any commercial or public use.
Save as expressly stated or as necessary to view, print or download extracts of the Material for personal use, none of the Material may be copied, edited, varied, reproduced, published, displayed, distributed, stored, transmitted, commercially exploited or disseminated in any form whatsoever without the prior written consent of The Diocese of Bristol or the relevant group company.
3. Content Submitted To The Website
Information, data, text, music, software, sound, photographs, graphics, video, messages or other materials may be posted or uploaded (in public or privately) on to designated areas of this Website. Any information, data, text, music, software, sound, photographs, graphics, video, messages or other materials which are posted or uploaded on to this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server or otherwise transmitted through this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server by any visitor to this Website is referred to as Content. The Diocese of Bristol does not control the Content and, as such, is not responsible for it in any way whatsoever.
In particular, The Diocese of Bristol does not guarantee the accuracy, integrity or quality of such Content. The Diocese of Bristol shall have the right (but not the obligation) in its sole discretion to delete, edit, lock, move or remove any Content without notice. Without limiting the foregoing, The Diocese of Bristol shall have the right without notice to record the IP address from which any Content is posted or uploaded to or otherwise transmitted through this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server and to lock or remove any Content which violates these Terms and Conditions or is or may be irrelevant, out of date, inappropriate or objectionable in any way whatsoever or in respect of which The Diocese of Bristol receives any complaint (whether valid, justified or not).
If you upload, post or otherwise transmit any Content to a public part of this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server (including, without limitation, if you post a message to a bulletin board or chat forum, upload files, input data, or engage in any other form of communication through this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site) you are wholly responsible for it. You hereby: (a) grant The Diocese of Bristol and its group companies an irrevocable, perpetual, royalty-free right to use, distribute, copy, edit, adapt, license, distribute, transmit, publish, publicly perform or display any such Content in any form or medium anywhere in the World; and (b) irrevocably and unconditionally waive any moral rights or similar rights you have in any Content pursuant to the Copyright, Designs and Patents Act 1988 (as amended, superseded or replaced from time to time) (the Act) or equivalent legislation anywhere in the World.
4. Link To Third Parties
This Website and other Diocese of Bristol Sites or Servers may contain links to websites operated by third parties (“Third Party Websites”). The Diocese of Bristol does not have any influence or control over any such Third Party Website and, unless otherwise stated, is not responsible for and does not endorse any Third Party Website or its availability or contents or any agreement or understanding you enter into with a third party through a Third Party Website.
5. Member Conduct
You agree that when using the Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server you will not:
1. Upload, post or otherwise transmit Content which violates the rights (including, without limitation, the intellectual property rights) of a third party or which is unlawful, harmful, threatening, abusive, argumentative, flaming, hateful, offensive (whether in relation to sex, race, religion or otherwise) harassing, defamatory, vulgar, obscene, indecent, libellous, invasive of anothers privacy or contains any illegal content;
2. Harvest Content or IP addresses or upload, post or otherwise transmit any Content which contains software viruses or any other files or programs that may interrupt, destroy or limit the functionality of this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server or any networks connected to this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server or anothers computer, or that contains any chain letters, pyramid-selling schemes, bulk mail, junk mail or similar; or
3. Upload, post or otherwise transmit any Content for any commercial or business purpose including (without limitation) any Content which contains any advertising or promotional materials; or
4. Restrict or in any way inhibit any person from using this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server;
5. Upload, post or otherwise transmit any Content which is un-necessary and/or repetitive including any Content which repeats that previously uploaded, posted or transmitted by you or another visitor, unless absolutely necessary; or
6. Upload, post or otherwise transmit any Content to a part of this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server which is irrelevant to the subject matter or the Content; or
7. Upload, post or otherwise transmit any Content to this Website or any Diocese of Bristol Site or Server using an e-mail address provided by a free account service.
8. Register yourself as a member of this Website, the forum provided through this Website, or to receive any newsletter or other service under more than one user name and/or user account number without the consent of the Website editor or the forum moderator; or
9. Use this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server in a manner that is inconsistent with these Terms and Conditions and/or any relevant laws and regulations in force from time to time; or
10. Breach the terms of any suspension or ban or seek alternative access. You acknowledge that you are solely responsible for maintaining a secure password for the purpose of gaining access to the member sections of this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server.
You agree to indemnify The Diocese of Bristol and its group companies in full and on demand from and against any loss, damage, costs or expenses which they suffer or incur directly or indirectly as a result of your use of this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server other than in accordance with these Terms and Conditions.
6. The Diocese of Bristol Privacy Policy
If you provide information to The Diocese of Bristol on or through this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server, The Diocese of Bristol will use it in accordance with the terms of its privacy policy. That privacy policy forms part of these Terms and Conditions and by using this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server you acknowledge and agree that you have read and accept the terms of that privacy policy.
7. Disclaimer / Liability
Use of this Website, any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server and their facilities, Third Party Websites, links to the Third Party Websites, and any Material and Content is at your own risk. To the maximum extent permitted by law: (a) The Diocese of Bristol disclaims all liability whatsoever, whether arising in contract, tort (including negligence) or otherwise in relation to this Website, any other The Diocese of Bristol Site or Server, Third Party Websites, links to Third Party Websites, Material and Content; and (b) all implied warranties, terms and conditions relating to this Website, any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server, Third Party Websites, links to Third Party Websites, Material and Content (whether implied by statue, common law or otherwise), including (without limitation) any warranty, term or condition as to accuracy, completeness, satisfactory quality, performance, fitness for purpose or any special purpose and title are, as between The Diocese of Bristol and you, hereby excluded. The Diocese of Bristol will not be liable, in contract, tort (including, without limitation, negligence), under statute or otherwise, as a result of or in connection with this Website, any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server, any Third Party Websites, links to Third Party Websites, the Material, Content, or any products or services offered on or through this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server or Third Party Website, whether by The Diocese of Bristol or on its behalf, for any:
economic loss (including, without limitation, loss of revenues, profits, contracts, business or anticipated savings); or
loss of goodwill or reputation; or
special or indirect or consequential loss.
If The Diocese of Bristol is liable to you directly or indirectly in relation to this Website, any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server, any Third Party Websites, links to Third Party Websites, the Material, Content, or any products or services offered on or through this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server or Third Party Website, that liability (howsoever arising) shall be limited to the sums paid by you in consideration for The Diocese of Bristol granting you membership to this Website.
Nothing in these Terms and Conditions shall be construed as excluding or limiting the liability of The Diocese of Bristol or its group companies for death or personal injury caused by its negligence or forany other liability which cannot be excluded by English law.
8. Access Restriction
The Diocese of Bristol reserves the right in its sole discretion to deny you access to this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server, or any portion thereof, without notice and for any reason including, without limitation, if you fail to comply with any clause 5 (“Member Conduct”) or any other provision of these Terms and Conditions. In particular, The Diocese of Bristol may deny you access to this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server if The Diocese of Bristol exercises its right to lock any discussion topic to prevent further discussion, following submission of Content relating to that topic by you.
9. Online Competitions
If you take part in any competition which is run on or through this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server (“Competition”), you agree to be bound by the Online Competition Rules and any other rules specified by The Diocese of Bristol from time to time (“Competition Rules”) and by the decisions of The Diocese of Bristol, which are final in all matters relating to the Competition. The Diocese of Bristol reserves the right to disqualify any entrant and/or winner in its absolute discretion without notice in accordance with the Competition Rules.
10. General
These Terms and Conditions (as amended from time to time) constitute the entire agreement between you and The Diocese of Bristol concerning your use of this Website or any other Diocese of Bristol Site or Server and supersede any previous arrangement, agreement, undertaking or proposal, written or oral between you and The Diocese of Bristol in relation to such matters. The Diocese of Bristol reserves the right to update these Terms and Conditions from time to time. If it does so, the updated version will be effective as soon as it is uploaded on to this Website. No other variation to these Terms and Conditions shall be effective unless in writing and signed by an
authorised representative on behalf of Diocese of Bristol.
These Terms and Conditions shall be governed by and construed in accordance with English law and you agree, for the benefit of The Diocese of Bristol, to submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the English Courts.
If any provision(s) of these Terms and Conditions is held by a court of competent jurisdiction to be invalid or unenforceable, then such provision(s) shall be construed, as nearly as possible, to reflect the intentions of the parties and all other provisions shall remain in full force and effect.
The Diocese of Bristol's failure to exercise or enforce any right or provision of these Terms and Conditions shall not constitute a waiver of such right or provision unless acknowledged and agreed to by The Diocese of Bristol in writing.
Unless otherwise expressly stated, nothing in the Terms and Conditions shall create any rights or any other benefits whether pursuant to the Contracts (Rights of Third Parties) Act 1999 or otherwise in favour of any person other than you, The Diocese of Bristol and its group of companies.
Privacy notice
The Bristol Diocesan Board of Finance Ltd (BDBF) is committed to respecting the privacy of all those for whom we hold personal information/data at any time. If you have any queries please do get in touch.
This Privacy Notice sets out the data protection and data privacy policies that fall within the oversight of the BDBF as a `Data Controller’ and it explains how your personal data is processed by the BDBF and for what purposes.
Read the Privacy Notice in full.
Resignation/prohibition notices
On 30 March 2020 a penalty of resignation and prohibition for life was imposed on the Reverend Philip John Paul Bradley under the Clergy Discipline Measure 2003 for adultery and performing unauthorised deliverance ministry.
Diocese of Bristol
First Floor Hillside House, 1500 Parkway North, Stoke Gifford, Bristol, BS34 8YU.
Staff Login.   Privacy notice and legal information.
T: 0117 906 0100
Send us an email
This website is powered by Church Edit
